<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Standards that can be used in an RRKive-compliant deployment on rrkive</title><link>https://www.rrkive.org/standards/</link><description>Recent content in Standards that can be used in an RRKive-compliant deployment on rrkive</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>info@rrkive.edu.au (rrkive)</managingEditor><webMaster>info@rrkive.edu.au (rrkive)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.rrkive.org/standards/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Metadata: Research Object Crate (RO-Crate)</title><link>https://www.rrkive.org/standards/ro-crate/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>info@rrkive.edu.au (rrkive)</author><guid>https://www.rrkive.org/standards/ro-crate/</guid><description>RO-Crate is a method for describing and packaging research data from ANY discipline into distributable, reusable Digital Objects with any amount of detailed metadata from simple who/what/where discovery-oriented description to metadata at the file-level or even variable level inside files.
RO-Crate is an implementer-focussed guide to best practice and is based on widely-used standards with schema.org annotations in JSON-LD and aims to make it easy to creat good quality metadata description tools which are accessible and practical for use in a wide variety of situations; from an individual researcher working with a folder of data, to large data-intensive computational research environments.</description></item><item><title>Standards: Oxford Common File Layout</title><link>https://www.rrkive.org/standards/ocfl/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>info@rrkive.edu.au (rrkive)</author><guid>https://www.rrkive.org/standards/ocfl/</guid><description>Oxford Common File Layout (OCFL) is a specification for laying out digital collections on file or object storage. It is designed with long-term preservation principles in mind; does not rely on specialised software and avoids the problem of locking data collections into monolithic repositories behind APIs.
An OCFL Repository is a system of directories laid out on a filesystem using a prescribed layout. Each repository contains one or more OCFL Objects.</description></item></channel></rss>